bookmarc.com.au 2017-02-18

# Bookmarc Online » Privacy Policy

### **BOOKMARC’s Privacy Statement**

**BOOKMARC’s commitment to maintaining your privacy**

BOOKMARC’s Privacy Statement has been created because we value our users and recognise their right to keep personal information private. This statement discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for all sites managed by BOOKMARC.

**Collecting information on BOOKMARC visitors**

BOOKMARC collects information on our site visitors collectively including which sections of the site are most frequently visited, how often and for how long. This data is always used as aggregated, non-personal information. BOOKMARC utilises this information to improve and enhance our services by monitoring the areas on the site which are most popular to you. This aggregated information may be shared with BOOKMARC partners to provide them with an overview of how BOOKMARC visitors use the site. This is done for the purposes of providing you with the best online platform for connecting designers in sourcing building & interior products/services.

**IP Addresses**

BOOKMARC’s web servers gather your IP address to assist with the diagnosis of problems or support issues with our services, and to monitor legitimate use of our site.

**Cookies & Applets**

BOOKMARC uses cookies to provide you with a better experience. These cookies and applets allow you to use specific services such as Auto Login to remember who you are for Auto Login if you choose this option and to remember your last search criteria for My Last Search.

**Third Party Measurement**

In order to better understand our users, BOOKMARC utilises a third party measurements to assess site traffic. A tracking code is used to collect the following information on the usage of the BOOKMARC site:

The number of page views (or page impressions) that occur on BOOKMARC;

The number of unique visitors to BOOKMARC;

How long these unique visitors (on average) spend on BOOKMARC when they do visit; and

Common entry and exit points into BOOKMARC.

This aggregate, non-personal information is collated and provided to BOOKMARC to assist in analysing the usage of the site.

**Collecting information on BOOKMARC Registered ‘My Account’ Members**

As part of registering with BOOKMARC, we collect personal information about you in order for you to take full advantage of BOOKMARC’s services. To do this it may be necessary for you to provide additional information to BOOKMARC as detailed below.

**Registration**

Registration is completely optional. However, registration for ‘My Account’ services allows you to take advantage of more of the tools and resources that assist you in finding your information. Registration includes submitting your email address. You may access this information at any time by clicking ‘Details’ on ‘My Account’.

**My BOOKMARCS**

My BOOKMARCS is an optional library collection service and can be shared across with other users & non-users of BOOKMARC. Users can modify or delete their My BOOKMARCS profiles at any time by going to the ‘All My Account’ area of the site. BOOKMARC accepts no liability or responsibility for information that is shared with users and non-users of the site which is of sensitive and private nature. My BOOKMARCS is secured library service. 

**Storing your BOOKMARCS**

BOOKMARC registered members are given a maximum 5GB storage allowance under ‘My BOOKMARCS’ area, with the option to purchase additional storage space per annum. Deleting a profile/image/CAD/technical content from My BOOKMARCS will mean it is no longer accessible to the registered member. Please note that deleted records may still be stored by BOOKMARC in testing or backup systems for a period of time. A recovery fee of $150 + GST will be applied for members who wish to recovery deleted data.

**BOOKMARC Profile**

BOOKMARC provides registered members (‘Supplier’) with the option of creating a personal profile. A profile includes your employment title, employer, contact details, and the locations (‘Profile’) registered members are situated. Registered members’ profiles can be seen by BOOKMARC users who seek product information, services and locations. Registered Members can modify or delete their profile at any time by going to the ‘My Account’ area of the site.

BOOKMARC reserves the right to disable or delete a Profile at their sole discretion.

**Email communications from BOOKMARC**

BOOKMARC also provides you with selected information about new to BOOKMARC suppliers, articles and project topics in our email newsletters of New to Bookmarc, Happy Monday, Daily Blog & Specification Generator. This free service is sent to registered users and provides the option of opting out of receiving these by changing your preferences within each newsletter or responding the email with unsubscribe. BOOKMARC may also make you aware of additional products and services which form part of your relationship with BOOKMARC.

**Storage & Security of Personal Information**

BOOKMARC takes all reasonable steps to ensure the security of our system. BOOKMARC allows you to access your information at any time to keep it accurate and up to date. Any information which we hold for you is stored on secure servers that are protected in controlled facilities.

In addition, our employees and the contractors who provide services related to our information systems are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by BOOKMARC. However, BOOKMARC will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access of your personal information.

You can also play an important role in keeping your personal information secure, by maintaining the confidentiality of any password and accounts used on the BOOKMARC site. Please notify us immediately if there is any unauthorised use of your account by any other Internet user or any other breach of security.

**Access to Your Information**

Unless you become a registered ‘My Account’ user, BOOKMARC does not collect information that identifies you personally. If however, you become a BOOKMARC registered user, you are able to change, update or delete your registered profile at any time by logging in to My Account.

**Data Transfers**

Sometimes, we transfer information to 3rd party contractors including persons outside Australia (e.g. a contractor located outside Australia who provides us with services). By giving us your personal information, you consent to such disclosures. In addition, where we transfer information to persons outside Australia we believe that the recipients of such information are subject to a law, binding scheme or contract which effectively upholds principles for fair handling of the information that are substantially similar to the National Privacy Principles.

**Feedback**

BOOKMARC welcomes ideas and feedback about all aspects of the site. BOOKMARC stores feedback that users send to us. This feedback will be used to administer and refine the service and may be shared with BOOKMARC partners either in aggregate form or with specific identifying characteristics removed. You may submit feedback via Contact Us.

**Privacy & Site Changes**

From time to time, BOOKMARC may review and update its privacy statement. Revised versions will be updated on the website.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with BOOKMARC, you can contact us in the following ways:

Email: [admin@Bookmarc.com.au](mailto:admin@Bookmarc.com.au)

Post: The Communications Director  
BOOKMARC Limited  
Suite 3  
173-179 Broadway  
Broadway NSW 2007  
Australia

**More Information About Privacy**

For more information about privacy issues in Australia and protecting your privacy, visit the Australian Federal Privacy Commissioner’s website.
